## **K.VENKATESAN**

4/136(2), Star City Theethipalayam (Near Kovai Kondattam) Coimbatore – 641010

Mob: 99944-11275

Email: venkataswincbe@gmail.com



**Objective** : To become an indispensable person in the Marketing industry And achieve the given Target through innovative Sales.

**Professional Summary:** 

A Marketing Professional with 30 years of experience. Significant expertise in Marketing and Sales Team Leading.

 Having Sales experience in Heavy Engineering Industries and Industrial Products.

 Having experience in Man Management, Team Coordination, ability to handle skilled and unskilled workforce.

Product Handled in Pneumatics, Electrical Drive,PA Products.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Present Employer : URD Motors Pvt Ltd. Coimbatore,

Designation : Sr Sales Engineer

Period : FEB 2022 - Till Date

Present Employer : Festo India Pvt Ltd. Coimbatore,

Designation : Sr Sales Engineer (Grade II)-Automotive Segment

Period : **OCT 2008 – 18.01.2021** 

Reporting To : Automotive Segment manager

Product : FESTO Pneumatic Products

Job Profile

 Promote all the Products in Coimbatore region Develop the New Customer.

Handling Key Account Customer.

Providing Technical knowledge to end user.

Selling New Product

Complete solution provider.

Responsibilities

Concentrating on Key Result Area.

Achieve the sales Target.

Monitoring the competitor activity.

## Achievements:

- Business generated 750 Lakes from M/s. Hirotec India.
   Continuous follow up and total technical support.
- Major customers: SPM,OEM and Automobile industries Pricol, Hirotec India, Quattro Engineering, Craftsman Automation, Ats-Elgi, Elgi Rubber.
- Introduction of more than 50 New customers in the Region.

## Previous Employer

## : HAVELLS INDIA LTD, Coimbatore

Designation : Sr Sales Engineer (Techno Commercial)

Period : Jan 2006 – Oct 2008 Reporting To : Branch manager

Product : Switch gears, MCB, RCCB, And DB Box etc.

## Job Profile

- Promote the all HAVELLS Products from Coimbatore to Tirupur region retail marketing and re-distribution.
- Distributors handled M/s.Vignesh Electric Company/ALSD Syndicate.
- Project handling by individual on site
- Organizing product promotional activities like licensed
- Electricians technical meeting with products launch...
- Coordinating with Top management, product end user.
- Doing Mapping for HAVELLS Products
- Handling All the DEALER network and Key Customers.
- Customers are Architects, Civil consultants, Electrical
- Consultants

## Responsibilities

- Achieve the sales Target by team coordination.
- Monitoring the competitor activity.
- Giving Presentation and Demo to the end user.
- Making the customer as 100% HAVELLS customer
- Motivate and coordinate the sale team to achieve the target.

## Achievements

- Got business at M/s. PRIME ENCLAVES, M/s. Mayflower Civil
- Builders, Ramani Builders Coimbatore.
- Achieved 50 % sales high on 2006.
- Achieved 30 % sales high on 2005.
- Highest sales of 7 Segment Db lighting Panel Boards in Tamilnadu zone.

## **Previous Employer**

## : ADOR WELDING LTD, Coimbatore.

Designation : Zonal Incharge-Sales
Period : Dec 2002 to Dec 2005.
Reporting To : Area Business Manager
Product : Welding machines, Welding

: Welding machines, Welding Electrodes and Accessories.

## Job Profile

- Promoting ADOR Products in Coimbatore and Tirupur
- Providing Technical Support to customers.

- Providing solution for welding related problem to Customer.
- Handling Key Account Customers LMW, PSG Foundry.
- Direct Marketing on all foundry and sugar industries.

## Responsibilities

- Achieve the sales Target by team coordination.
- Monitoring the competitor activity.
- Preparing the Sales Analysis for forecast.

#### **Achievements**

- Target is 90 lakh per annum as performed positively.
- 8 Nos of MIG welding, machine with 400 Amps sold in M/s Super springs worth 5 lakh.
- Sales increased 18 lakh per year in a given target in 1month.

Previous Employer : COIMBATORE MACHINARY & METAL MART,

Coimbatore.

Designation : Sr Executive-marketing
Period : June 1996 to Nov 2002.
Reporting To : Managing Director

Product : CHICAGO PNEUMATIC TOOLS and LEGRIS PNEUMATIC

#### Job Profile:

- Looking after CP Pneumatic tools and LEGRIS Pneumatic Products
- AEG Electric Power tools (Drilling, Hammer Drill, Demolishing Equipments and Electric screw drivers,)
- Direct marketing in all engineering Industries.
- Complete sales in whole Salem Dist & Coimbatore Dist.
- All Automobile authorized workshops for 2 & 4 wheelers service centers.

## **Achievements:**

- CAG TAFE implemented all pneumatic tools and equipments
- Turn key process works handled in all Automobile sectors.

Previous Employer : HMP ENGINEERS, Coimbatore.

Designation : Marketing Officer
Period : June 1991 to May 1996
Reporting To : Area Manager-Sales

Product : RALLI WOLF-Electrical Power Tools.

## Job Profile:

HMP ENGINEERS LTD is a manufactures of RALLI WOLF electric power tools in Mumbai, The Company has its core business in Customized in all industries.

- Direct Marketing in all engineering Industries in Coimbatore.
- Through Dealer network CBE exclusively.

- Customers' ranges are all type of Small scale to large scale industries.
- Handling Electric hand grinding machine and deburrintg tools.

## **COMPUTER PROFICIENCY:**

MS-DOS Operating Systems, OFFICE 2003 and OFFICE 2007 POWER POINT and OUTLOOK EXPRESS 2007.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

SSLC : Ramakrishna saradha higher secondary school, Salem

Percentage Of marks : 63% Period : 1986-1987

## TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION:

Diploma in Mechanical Engg : Thiagarajar Polytechnic, Salem

Board of Technical Education, Chennai.

Percentage Of marks : 61% Period : 1988-1991

## Personal Information:

Sex : Male
Date of Birth : 19.03.1970
Father's Name : A.Krishnamoorthy
Languages Speak : English, Tamil, Telugu,
Languages Write : English, Tamil.
Languages Read : English, Tamil, Hindi

## **Permanent Address:**

Ste no: 39, Star City,

Theethipalayam (Near Kovai Kondattam),

Coimbatore-641010. Phone No: 99944-11275

Total CTC Per Annum: 12.36 L